franklintempletonindia.com 2019-11-07

# Security & Privacy

We respect your privacy and value the trust you place in us when you share your personal information with us. The way we may use your personal information is discussed in our official privacy notice. Having said that, we know you might have some additional questions about privacy on the Web. 

First, we will talk about privacy as it relates to using this website. Then, we will cover the broader privacy issues concerning a mutual fund shareholder's relationship with our company as a whole. If you want to skip the Web-related privacy issues, you can jump ahead and read our official Mutual Fund Privacy Notice.

**Web-Related Privacy Issues**

**How we use information provided on the Web**

**Your email address:**  We collect your email address when you register for account access. If we need to contact you about transactions or account activity on the site, your email address lets us do that quickly. If you sign up for electronic delivery of documents, we will need your email address for that, too.

Even if you are not registered for account access, we may need to ask for your email address. For instance, if you ask for a referral to a financial adviser or subscribe to our email newsletter, we'll need your email address to respond to your requests.

We won't send emails you have not asked for unless there is a good reason.

**Survey information:** Occasionally we may ask you to participate in a brief survey to help us make smart choices as we look for ways to improve the site. If you choose to participate, information you provide won't be identified with you personally.

**Personal data entered in calculators** : When you use calculators and planning tools on the site, you may need to enter information such as your age or even certain dollar amounts like how much you save each month.

We do not collect or store this kind of information. It is only used to perform the calculation you are asking for.

**Our Mutual Fund Privacy Notice**

**Your Privacy Is Our Priority**

Franklin Templeton Investments including Franklin Templeton Asset Management (India) Pvt. Ltd (AMC) and Franklin Templeton Trustee Services Pvt. Ltd are committed to safeguarding information provided to us by Unitholders of schemes of Franklin Templeton Mutual Fund in India. This notice is designed to provide you with a summary of the non-public personal information we may collect and maintain about current or former investors; our policy regarding the use of that information; and the measures we take to safeguard the information. We do not sell non-public personal information to anyone and only share it as described in this notice.

**Information We Collect**

When you invest in the schemes of Franklin Templeton Mutual Fund, India you provide us with your non-public personal information. We collect and use this information to service your accounts and respond to your requests. The non-public personal information we collect falls into the following categories:

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms, whether we receive the form in writing or electronically. For example, this information includes your name, address, tax identification number, birth date, investment selection, beneficiary information, and possibly your personal bank account information and/or email address if you are signing up for certain account options.
  * Information about your transactions and account history with us, or with other companies that are part of Franklin Templeton Investments, including transactions you request on our website. This category also includes your communications to us concerning your investments.
  * Other general information that we may obtain about you such as demographic information.

**Some of the information mentioned above can be personal and sensitive in nature as per the indicative list given below:**

  * Bank Account details change of bank account details or registration of multiple bank accounts etc. through application forms;
  * Payment instrument details at the time of submitting application at the time of investment or as proof for carrying out change of bank account or any other details of debit card obtained (if any);
  * Generation and storing password (PIN) in encrypted form based on the request from the investor under the online mode of investments;
  * Biometric information obtained, if any;
  * Demat Account details like beneficiary account no. etc.;
  * Annual Income and savings profile; and
  * Other information as may be considered as sensitive and personal

**Disclosure Policy**

The aforesaid information is being collected by the AMC/Service Providers to respond to your requests, to process the investment applications and to also ensure safe subscriptions/redemptions through points of acceptance in physical form, website, online portals, Automated Teller Machines and such other mode. The AMC may also call the investors to inform them with respect to the other products or services offered by the AMC. The said information is also being collected to be compliant with the Know Your Client (KYC) norms under the Prevention of Money Laundering Act, 2002, (PMLA), the rules issued thereunder, and guidelines and circular on Anti- Money Laundering issued by SEBI and SEBI (Mutual Funds) Regulations, 1996 as amended till date. 

The aforesaid information is the basis of our ability to provide investors/clients/customers with good, qualitative, timely and efficient service, customized and personalized experience, while also keeping the information and data provided totally secure and confidential. 

We endeavor to have suitable technical, operational and physical security controls and measures to protect investors/customers/clients personal/sensitive data or information that are commensurate with the nature of our business at all times. 

We permit only authorized employees who are trained in the proper handling of customer information, to have access to aforesaid information. We would ensure to enter into suitable terms with third party service providers in order to protect client confidentiality and follow a non-disclosure or restricted disclosure policy. Further, the employees who violate the privacy and confidentiality promise shall be subjected to disciplinary action. 

We shall reveal only such information to external authorities as may be found relevant and necessary in order to comply with the applicable laws of the land and to third party service providers to ensure smooth functioning of the activities as may be prescribed under applicable laws like Registrar and Transfer Agents/distributors/banks/sub-brokers/call-centers/custodians/depositories and such other entities/persons. By using our website or by agreeing to transact with us, you agree to the above sharing of information during your relationship with us. We may also be required from time to time to disclose investors/customers/clients personal information to governmental or judicial bodies or agencies or our regulators based on their requirement to comply with the applicable laws including cyber laws. In addition to the above we may also use the information shared by investors/clients/customers to contact investors/clients/customers regarding the products and services offered by us and seek feedback on the services provided. Further, such information may also be used by us to generate statistics and reports and/or to protect and defend the rights, interest and property of the Mutual Fund, AMC, Trustee Company, Sponsors & its affiliates and directors and/or to enforce legal rights or provisions of the Scheme related Documents of the Mutual Fund viz. Scheme Information Document (SID), Statement of Additional Information (SAI) and Key Information Memorandum (KIM). To better service your accounts and provide you with more choices, we may share non-public personal information with other Franklin Templeton Investments' companies such as investment advisers, the distributor of our mutual funds, and financial service providers offering banking, trust, and custodial products and services. Further, it may be noted that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser supplied information and site session information may be recorded as part of the normal operations and for security monitoring purposes. 

Nevertheless, it is our foremost endeavor to ensure that the Customer’s Privacy is protected at all points in time. The customers/clients (whether existing/prospective) must ensure to recheck the information or data being provided to the AMC or any person acting on its behalf. Incase if any of the data/information is found to be inaccurate or incorrect, the same shall be informed to the AMC for immediate amendment. The AMC and any person acting on its behalf shall not be responsible for the authenticity of the personal information or sensitive personal data or information supplied by the customers/clients (whether existing/prospective). 

Our website may use cookies. By using our website and agreeing to these terms of use, you consent to our use of cookies in accordance with the terms of our privacy policy. 

Investors/ Customers/ Clients shall not be covered by the terms of this Policy if they access other websites using links from this website. 

Further, despite our efforts to protect investors/customers/clients privacy, if unauthorized persons breach security control measures and illegally use such sensitive/personal data or information, the Mutual Fund, AMC, Trustee Company, Sponsors and its affiliates and directors shall not be held responsible/liable.

**Amendments/Modifications  
** This Privacy Policy available on our website is current and valid. However, the AMC reserves the right to amend/modify any of the sections of this policy at any time and the clients/customers/investors are requested to keep themselves updated for changes by reading the same from time to time. 

**Retention of information/data  
** It may be noted that we may retain the data as may be provided by the client/investors/customers till such time as may be provided under the law and as required to efficiently provide service to the clients/investors/customers.

**Grievance redressal  
** If investors/customers/clients have any concerns relating to their personal and sensitive information they may be addressed to Investor Relations Officer. For more details please refer to the Scheme related documents available on our website.   
Investors/clients/customers shall have expressly consented to the terms of this Policy if they enter and use this website or provide any information while transacting with us.
